So here is the left factor grammar now type out neatly. And we
这就是现在打字整齐的左因数语法。而我们
use this grammar to construct a parsing table. And let's not worry right now about
使用此语法构建解析表。我们现在不用担心
how we got this table, I'm not gonna give the algorithm right now. But, let's just say
我们是怎么弄到这张桌子的，我现在不会给出算法。但是，这么说吧
that we got it somehow. And, what I'm going to explain is how we got the table.
我们以某种方式得到了它。我要解释的是我们是怎么弄到这张桌子的。
So, One dimension of the table is the current left most, non-terminal in the par
因此，表的一个维度是当前最左边的非终结点
stream. That's on the rows. And then the columns represent the next input token So,
溪流。那是排成一排的。然后这些列表示下一个输入令牌So，
the next token in the input stream. And, then the entry is the right hand side of the
输入流中的下一个令牌。然后，条目就是
production to use. So, which production that we should used at that point
要使用的产品。那么，在这一点上我们应该使用哪种产品呢
in the pars. That's the production that's predicted. So let's do an example.
在帕尔斯。这就是预测的产量。让我们举个例子。
So let's look at E INT entry. So this entry right here. Now what this says is that
那么让我们来看一下E，int条目。所以这个条目就在这里。这上面说的是
when the current nonterminal is E, meaning the left most nonterminal on the parks
当当前非终端为E时，表示公园中最左侧的非终端
tree and the next input is in, the thing that we see coming up in the input is
树，下一个输入在中，我们在输入中看到的内容是
an integer. Then we should use the production E goes to TX. So we should expand
一个整数。那么我们应该用生产E去德克萨斯州。所以我们应该扩大规模
E with the children TX. Let's do another example. So when the current non-terminal
E和孩子们一起去德克萨斯州。让我们再举一个例子。所以当当前的非终端
is Y and the current token, the current input is plus, then we should
是Y并且是当前令牌，则当前输入是加号，那么我们应该
use the production Y goes to epsilon. Okay, what that says is, it's a little bit
使用产品Y转到epsilon。好的，上面说的是，这有点
different situation than the previous one, it says look when you see a plus in the input
与前一种情况不同，它说当您在输入中看到加号时请查看
and your current left most non-terminal is y, the only way this parse
当前最左边的非终结符是y，这个解析的唯一方法
is going to succeed is if the y doesn't produce anything. You need to get rid of the
如果y不产生任何东西，它就会成功。你需要去掉那些
y and move on to a nother non-terminal whichever one is left-most after you get rid
y，然后移动到另一个非终端，不管哪个是剩下的-大多数是在你摆脱之后。
of the y. If you want to have any hope of parsing this particular string. And finally,
如果您想要有任何希望解析这个特定的字符串。最后，
notice that a lot of the entries are blank and those are error entries. So
请注意，许多条目为空，这些条目是错误条目。所以
let's take a look at the E star entry. That says that if the leftmost non terminal
我们来看一下E星条目。也就是说，如果最左边的非终端
is E and the next input token is a time symbol, a star. Well, then there is
是E，下一个输入令牌是时间符号，即星号。嗯，那就有
no move that you can make. There is, there is no production you can use for E that's
你不能采取任何行动。没有可以用于E的产品，那就是
going to successfully parse that input. And this is the point at which you would raise
将成功解析该输入。在这一点上，你会提出
a parsing error. In the rest of this video, I'm gonna give the algorithm for parsing
分析错误。在这段视频的睡觉中，我将给出解析算法
using a parsing table. And then in future videos, we'll explain how to construct
使用解析表。在以后的视频中，我们将解释如何构建
a parsing table. So the method for parsing using a parsing table is similar
解析表。因此，使用解析表进行解析的方法是类似的
to recursive descent. Expect that for the leftmost non terminal S in the tree,
到递归下降。期望对于树中最左边的非终端S，
we look at the next input token A. And then as we just illustrated with the examples,
我们查看下一个输入令牌A，然后正如我们刚才用示例说明的那样，
we look up in the table the production to use at the low, at the, at the
我们在表中查到最低处、最低处、最低处的产量
entry S, A. And instead of using recursive functions, to trace out the parse
条目S、A，并且不使用递归函数来跟踪解析
tree, we're going to have a stack of records that can, record the frontier. And
树，我们会有一叠记录，可以记录边疆。和
so at any point in the [inaudible] tree we will have some non-terminals that have yet
因此，在(听不见的)树中的任何点上，我们都会有一些尚未
to be expanded. Those are always at the frontier at the current leaves of the [inaudible]
待扩展。那些总是在边疆的[听不见的]当前的树叶
tree. And also there are some terminals that we have yet to match against.
树。还有一些终端我们还没有与之匹配。
Those will all be recorded out of stack. The important property of the stack
这些都将记录在堆叠之外。堆栈的重要属性
is that the left most pending terminal or non-terminal is always at the top of the stack.
最左边的挂起终端或非终端始终位于堆栈的顶部。
So, either the terminal we are trying to match or the non-terminal we are
因此，要么是我们试图匹配的终端，要么是我们所在的非终端
trying to expand will always be on top of our stack. We'll reject if we reach an error
努力扩张永远是我们的头等大事。如果我们犯了错误，我们会拒绝的
state. So if we look up one of those empty entries in the table, we will reject
州政府。因此，如果我们在表中查找其中一个空条目，我们将拒绝
the string. And we'll accept if we reach the end of the input, and we have an empty
那根绳子。如果我们到达输入的末尾，我们会接受，我们有一个空的
stack. Meaning we have no pending unmatched terminals or unexpanded non terminals.
堆栈。这意味着我们没有挂起的未匹配终端或未扩展的非终端。
So, here's the algorithm, we initialize the stack to just the start symbol
所以，这是算法，我们将堆栈初始化为开始符号
S and a special symbol $. The $ is not a part of the alphabet or you can think
s和特殊符号$。$不是字母表的一部分，或者您可以认为
of it we extend wherever our alphabet is with a new symbol $. $ Marks the
无论我们的字母表在哪里，我们都会用一个新符号$来扩展它。$标记
mottom of the stack and you can think of it also as marking the end of input. So,
堆栈的座右铭，您也可以将其视为输入结束的标志。所以,
this is just a way of recording where the end of the input is going to be. Okay,
这只是一种记录输入结束位置的方式。好吧,
so the, so once we've matched, something against S, then whatever's left, it better
所以，所以一旦我们匹配了一些东西来对抗S，那么不管剩下的是什么，它都会更好
be at the end of the input. That's what the, that stack, expresses. And now we're
在输入的末尾。这就是那个，那个堆栈所表达的意思。现在我们是
at a loop, so we're gonna repeat the following moves until; we can't repeat them
在一个循环中，所以我们将重复下面的动作，直到；我们不能重复它们
anymore Until the stack is empty. Okay? And there's two possible moves. Let's
直到堆栈为空。好吧?有两种可能的行动。我们走吧
do the terminals first. So let's say the top of our stack is a terminal. So here
先把终端做一下。我们假设堆栈的顶部是一个终端。所以在这里
we're dividing the stack to the top of the stack and the rest of the stack. So,
我们将堆栈划分为堆栈的顶部和堆栈的睡觉。所以,
what are we going to do if the top of the stack is a terminal? Well we're going
如果堆栈的顶部是终端，我们该怎么办？好的，我们要走了
to try to match the input. So we're going to say well if the top of the stack, the terminal
尝试匹配输入。所以我们会说，如果堆栈的顶部，终端
on top of the stack, matches the next thing in the input, then we advance the
在堆栈顶部，匹配输入中的下一项，然后我们将
input. And we pop the stack. So we have successfully matched the input against
输入。然后我们弹出堆栈。所以我们已经成功地将输入与
the, the terminal. And so that terminal is done, and we should progress into
这个，这个航站楼。航站楼已经完工，我们应该进入
the stack, and match the next thing that hasn't been handled yet. And if they
堆栈，并匹配下一个尚未处理的内容。如果他们
don't match, if the terminal that we are looking at doesn't match the next thing in
不匹配，如果我们正在查看的终端与
the input, well, that's an error. We don't have any backtracking here. There's no way
输入，嗯，那是个错误。我们这里没有任何回头路。这是不可能的
to parse the string, so we'll raise [inaudible]. Now the second class of moves
来解析字符串，因此我们将引发[不可闻]。现在是第二类动作
is deals with the non-terminal. So let's say at the top of the stack is the non-terminal
是和非终点站打交道的。我们假设堆栈的顶部是非终结符
x. So remember that the top of the stack will be a non-terminal, exactly
x.所以请记住，堆栈的顶部将是一个非终结点，准确地说
when that is the left most non-terminal. So now what we, now what we
当那是最左边的非终结点时。所以现在我们，现在我们
do is we look at our pricing table under the entry for x and the next input symbol
我们要做的是查看x条目下的定价表和下一个输入符号
and that should give us the right hand side of a production. Okay? And now what we
这应该会给我们带来一部作品的右手边。好吧?现在我们要做的是
do is we pop X off the stack, and we push the, the children of X i n the parse
我们要做的就是将X从堆栈中弹出，并将X的子级推入解析
tree under the stack. So this is the way we expand X. So now, the leftmost unhandled
堆栈下面的树。这就是我们展开X的方式，所以现在，最左边的未处理
thing in the parse is going to be Y1, because that's the first child of X.
解析中的值将是Y1，因为它是X的第一个子级。
And then all the other children of X are next. And then whatever else is in the
然后X的所有其他子代就是下一个。然后不管里面还有什么
stack. And again, if there's no entry, for, the current non terminal and input in
堆栈。同样，如果没有条目，则当前的非终端和输入
the table, then that's an error, and the parsing stops. So let's through an example
表，那么这就是一个错误，解析就停止了。那么让我们通过一个例子
using our, pricing table, and. You might want to refer back to the parsing table, have
使用我们的、定价表和。您可能希望回过头来参考解析表，
not included it here, because there isn't space for it. But I'll work through
这里没有包括它，因为没有空间放它。不过，我会熬过去的
it, and you can go back and look at it at some point, and convince yourself that I'd
你可以在某个时候回去看看它，然后说服自己我会
made the right moves. So initially, our stack is E$. So E was our start symbol, and
做出了正确的举动。所以最初，我们的堆栈是E$。所以E是我们的开始符号
$ is our end of input symbol. And our input, we're gonna try to parse the input
$是我们的输入结束符号。我们的输入，我们将尝试解析输入
[inaudible] times [inaudible], that's what we want to parse. And then, of course, we
[听不见]倍[听不见]，这就是我们要分析的。然后，当然，我们
have our new symbol $, we'll tack that onto the end of the input. And if all goes
有了我们的新符号$，我们将把它添加到输入的末尾。如果一切顺利
well, the dollar sign on the stack will match up against the dollar sign at the end
嗯，堆叠上的美元符号将与末尾的美元符号相匹配
of the input. Again, dollar sign here is just a way of marking. The end of the input
输入的数据。再说一遍，这里的美元符号只是一种标记方式。输入的末尾
and expressing that we need to parse the entire input. And so now if you look up
并表示我们需要解析整个输入。所以现在如果你抬头看
the E int entry, so the first terminal in the, the next terminal in the input and
E int条目，因此中的第一个端子、输入中的下一个端子和
the left most [inaudible] terminal in our parse, you would see that we're actually supposed
解析中最左边的[听不见]终端，您会看到我们实际上应该
to take is to use the production E goes to TX. And let me over here at the
拿就是用产品E去德克萨斯州。让我在这里的
same time construct our pars-trey. 'Kay, so initially our stack, again, the stack is
同时构建我们的分析树。好的，所以最初我们的堆栈，再一次，堆栈是
the frontier of the parstrey. Initially, all we have is the root of the
牧场的边疆地区。最初，我们所拥有的只是
parstrey and that is its own frontier, it's just one symbol, we haven't processed
那是它自己的边界，它只是一个符号，我们还没有处理
it yet. And so E is on the stack, E is unexpanded in the parstrey, and now we're
还没有。所以E在堆栈上，E在行列式中未展开，现在我们
going to use the production E goes to TX. So we'll have, T and X added as children.
要使用生产E去德克萨斯州。所以我们会把T和X作为孩子加起来。
What happens next? Well E is popped off the stack. T and X are pushed on to the stack.
接下来会发生什么？好的，E从堆栈中弹出。T和X被压入堆栈。
And now notice the frontier of the parse tree, is TX. So t hese is usually unprocessed
现在请注意解析树的边界是tx。所以这些通常是未经处理的
leaves Either unmatched input or unexpanded non-terminals And in fact the
留下不匹配的输入或未扩展的非终端，事实上
stack records exactly which one is left most. So T is at the top of the stack.
堆栈准确地记录了哪一个是最左边的。所以T在堆栈的顶部。
X is below it, on the stack. Okay well we still haven't consumed any input.
X在它的下面，在堆栈上。好的，我们仍然没有消耗任何输入。
And now if we look at the T, int entry it says to use T goes to int Y. And so now we
现在如果我们看一下T，它说使用T变成了，所以现在我们
can expand T by [inaudible] y. And now what's going to happen is T is popped off
可以将T扩展[听不见]y。现在将会发生的是T被弹出
the stack. Int and Y are pushed onto the stack and now notice the stack is Int Y X
堆栈。将INT和Y推送到堆栈上，现在请注意堆栈是Int Y X
from top to bottom. The frontier of the parse tree is Int Y X. Okay? And now we have
从上到下。解析树的边界是Int Y X，好吗？现在我们有了
a case where we have a terminal on top of the stack. And so now we're gonna try
在这种情况下，我们在堆栈的顶部有一个终端。所以现在我们要试着
to match it against the first terminal in the input and indeed they match. And so
将其与输入中的第一个端子进行匹配，并且它们确实匹配。因此，
what happens is [inaudible] just popped off the stack and the terminal and sorry the
发生的事情是[听不见]刚刚从堆栈和终端中弹出，抱歉
input pointer advances in the input. Here I've recorded that by just discarding
输入指针在输入中前进。我在这里记录了这一点，只需丢弃
the portion of the input that we've processed. So now we have [inaudible] left
我们已处理的输入部分。所以现在我们只剩下[听不见]了
to go and the inch has been removed from the stack. And so now what's on top of the
带走，英寸已经从堆叠中移走了。所以现在最重要的是
stack is Y. Y is indeed the leftmost unprocessed thing on the frontier. And, the
堆栈是Y，Y确实是边界上最左边未处理的东西。而且，这个
table says that, for non terminal Y, on, input times, we should use production
表中显示，对于非终端Y、ON、输入时间，我们应该使用生产
Y goes to times T. So let's put that in here. And now what's going to happen. Y is
Y表示乘以T，所以我们把它放在这里。现在我们来看看接下来会发生什么。Y是
going to be popped off the stack. Times T is going to be pushed on to the stack. And
将从堆栈中弹出。乘以T将被压入堆栈。和
now notice our stack is times T, X and the frontier, the unprocessed frontier of the
现在请注意，我们的堆栈是乘以T、X和边界，即未处理的边界
parse tree is times T X. Okay. So now we have another terminal on top of the stack,
解析树是乘以T×X的，好的。所以现在我们在堆栈的顶部有了另一个终端，
it matches the next terminal in the input. So we pop the terminal off the stack, we advance
它与输入中的下一个端子匹配。所以我们把终端从堆栈上弹出来，我们前进
the input player. Now we have T as our left most nonterminal. Int is the next
输入播放器。现在我们将T作为最左边的非终结点。INT是下一个
thing in the input stream and the table says, well in this situation, we should use
输入流中的内容，表中显示，在这种情况下，我们应该使用
the production T goes from INT Y.  What does that mean? That means that T gets popped
T是从int Y开始的，这是什么意思？这意味着T会被弹出
of the stack. Int and Y get pushed onto the stack. Notice that the stack is Int,
堆栈中的。INT和Y被压入堆栈。请注意，堆栈是Int，
Y, X, and the end process frontier of the parse t ree from left to right is Int,
Y，X，并且解析树从左到右的结束进程边界是Int，
Y, X. Once again we have a terminal on top of the stack, we match it against the next
Y，X。再一次，我们在堆栈的顶部有一个终端，我们将它与下一个终端进行匹配
terminal in the input string, they match. And now we have consumed all the input, dollar
输入字符串中的终端，则它们匹配。现在我们已经消耗了所有的投入，美元
sign is the only thing left to go in the input. But our stack is not empty.
标牌是唯一需要输入的东西。但是我们的堆栈不是空的。
Okay and so at this point what does that mean. Well, if the stack is not empty and
好的，那么在这一点上，这意味着什么。如果堆栈不是空的
we are out of input then everything that's left on the stack had better generate the
我们没有输入了，那么堆栈上剩下的所有东西最好都生成
empty strings. So we'd better be using only epsilon productions from here on and
空字符串。所以我们最好从现在开始只使用epsilon产品
indeed the table says that when Y is our next non terminal and dollar sign we are at
事实上，表格上说，当Y是我们的下一个非终结点和美元符号时，我们就在
the end of the input we should use the production Y goes to epsilon. So Y goes to
输入的末尾，我们应该使用乘积Y转到epsilon。所以Y去了
epsilon that means Y just gets pop off the stack. Epsilon gets pushed on the stack; epsilon
Epsilon，这意味着Y只是从堆栈中取出POP。epsilon被推送到堆栈上；epsilon
is the empty string so nothing gets pushed on the stack. And now we're down
是空字符串，因此不会将任何内容推送到堆栈上。现在我们倒下了
to X and in the situation where X is the next non-terminal dollar sign is, we're
在X是下一个非终端美元符号的情况下，我们
at the end of the input so dollar sign is our next symbol. Then the table also
在输入的末尾，所以美元符号是我们的下一个符号。那么这张桌子也
says to use production X goes to epsilon. And then what happens? Well, X gets
说要用生产X去epsilon。然后会发生什么呢？嗯，X得到了
popped off the stack and nothing gets pushed on because the production was X goes
从堆栈中弹出，没有任何事情被推入，因为制作是X Go
to the empty string. And now we see we have dollar sign on top of the stack, dollar
添加到空字符串。现在我们看到堆栈的顶部有美元符号，美元
sign in the input. And so we have emptied the stack. We have, reached the end
在输入内容上签名。所以我们已经清空了堆栈。我们已经，走到了尽头
of the input, and so we accept. That is a successful parse.
所以我们接受了。这是一个成功的解析。